Thomas Moore Papers
Thomas Moore Papers
- Audiovisual material
  - Miscellaneous, most of these are homemade tapes with handwritten labels
    - Kathleen Jenks: Woman's Way: Beyond the Hero (8 of 9), 4/12/97; collection has only 2 of the 9 tapes in this set; moore_t_057; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 2)
    - Man Alive - Care of the Soul, 1/26/1994; moore_t_008; Prod.: F. M. Morrison.; VHS; running time 30:00 (Box 1)
    - Myth of Childhood, parts 1 and 2, moore_t_023; VHS; running time 90:00 (Box 1)
    - Myth of Childhood, part 3, moore_t_024; VHS (Box 1)
    - The Sacred and the Ordinary, Febryary 25, 1995; moore_t_015; VHS; running time 1:14:16 (Box 1)
    - Thomas Moore (edit master), moore_t_029; VHS; running time 120:00 (Box 1)
    - Thomas Moore (rough edit 1 of 2), 4/97; moore_t_021; note on the label reads "With Sunset and book scroll at end"; VHS; running time 12:30 (Box 1)
    - Tom Moore (rough edit 2 of 2), 4/97; moore_t_022; VHS; running time 30:00 (Box 1)
    - Thomas Moore Father's Day Satellite Press Tour history tape (1 of 2), June 14, 1995; moore_t_016; VHS; running time 60:00 (Box 1)
    - Thomas Moore Father's Day Satellite Press Tour history tape (2 of 2), June 14, 1995; moore_t_017; VHS; running time 60:00 (Box 1)
    - Thomas Moore: Re-Enchantment, Boston #1, 10/16/94; moore_t_050; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 2)
    - Thomas Moore: Re-Enchantment, Boston #2, 10/16/94; moore_t_051; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 2)
    - Thomas Moore: The Re-Enchantment of Everyday Life, Pacifica Graduate Institute Tape 3, 05/21/95; incomplete; tapes 1 and 2 not found; moore_t_052; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 2)
- Correspondence
  - A, misc (Box 4)
  - Bailey, Jonathan (Box 4)
  - Bantam Books (Box 4)
  - Bassett, Carrie (Box 4)
  - Brophy, Thomas (Box 4)
  - B, misc (Box 4)
  - C, misc (Box 4)
  - D, misc (Box 4)
  - Estes, Clarissa Pinkola (Box 4)
  - E, misc (Box 4)
  - F, misc (Box 4)
  - Gablik, Suzi (Box 4)
  - Gottlieb, Annie (Box 4)
  - G, misc (Box 4)
  - Harper Collins, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Howell, Alice and Walter (Box 4)
  - Huyler, Stephen P. (Box 4)
  - H, misc (Box 4)
  - L'Immaginale (Box 4)
  - Interface (Box 4)
  - Journeymen (Box 4)
  - J, misc (Box 4)
  - K, misc (Box 4)
  - Larson Publications (Box 5)
  - L, misc (Box 5)
  - Marshall, Laurie (Box 5)
  - McKnight, Tom (Box 5)
  - Moyers, Bill (Box 5)
  - M, misc (Box 5)
  - New York Center for Jungian Studies (Aryeh Maidenbaum) (Box 5)
  - Nickelsburg, George (Box 5)
  - Novak, Philip (Box 5)
  - Noel, Dan (Box 5)
  - N-O, misc (Box 5)
  - Pardi, Roy (Box 5)
  - Pearlman, Bill (Box 5)
  - P, misc (Box 5)
  - Rabushka, Aaron, J. (Box 5)
  - Reinhart, Peter (Box 5)
  - Rosen, David H. (Box 5)
  - R, misc (Box 5)
  - The Salt Journal (Box 5)
  - Sardello, Robert (Box 5)
  - Schenk, Ronald (Box 5)
  - Shepheard-Walwyn Ltd, publishes of Ficino book (Box 5)
  - Slattery, Dennis P. (Box 5)
  - Stroud, Joanne H. (Box 5)
  - S, misc (Box 5)
  - Texas State Board of Examiners (Box 5)
  - Theroux, Phyllis (Box 5)
  - T, misc (Box 5)
  - Vernon, Mary (Box 5)
  - Voss, Angela (Box 5)
  - V, misc (Box 5)
  - W, Y, misc (Box 5)
  - Unidentified, first name only (Box 5)
  - Unidentified, no name (Box 5)
- Manuscripts
  - The Soul of Sex
    - Early draft, with corrections, 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Publisher notes (Box 6)
    - Setting copy, with corrections, 2 folders (Box 6)
    - First proofs, with corrections, 3 folders (Box 6)
- Memorabilia
  - Catalogs
    - Harper Collins, 1995-1996; 1999-2000; 3 folders (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 7)
  - Clippings
    - Articles about, 1992-1999; 2003-2004; 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Book reviews, 1992-1998; 2000; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Publicity
    - Books (Box 7)
    - Lectures and workshops (Box 7)
  - "Spirituality and Health" vol, 1 and 2, bound, presentation copy for Moore, with his name embossed in silver on front (Box 8)
- Writings
  - Books
    - The Book of Job with commentary by Thomas Moore, Riverhead Books, 1998; paperback; 2 copies (Box 9)
    - Care of the soul in medicine, Hay House, 2010; hardcover (Box 9)
    - Care of the soul, the illustrated edition, Harper Collins, 1998; hardcover (Box 9)
    - The Education of the heart, Harper Collins, 1997; uncorrected proof (Box 9)
    - The Guru of golf, Hay House, 2010; hardcover (Box 9)
    - Meditations: On the monk who dwells in daily life, Harper Collins, 1994; hardcover (Box 9)
    - A Life at work, Broadway Books, 2008; hardcover (Box 9)
    - Original self, Harper Collins, 2000; uncorrected proof (Box 9)
    - Rituals of the imagination, Pegasus Foundation, 1983; paperback (Box 9)
    - Soul mates, Harper Collins, 1994; hardcover (Box 9)
    - The Soul of sex, Harper Collins, 1998; hardcover (Box 9)
    - The Soul's religion, Harper Collins, 2002; hardcover (Box 9)
    - Writing in the sand: Jesus & the soul of the gospels, Hay House, 2009; hardcover (Box 9)
  - Books, foreign language editions, French, German, Japanese, Spanish, etc.
    - Miscellaneous (Box 9)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 10)
  - Chapters
    - "Annunciation" in The Angels, edited by Robert Sardello, 1994; paperback (Box 11)
    - "The Artist: Therapist as magus" in Spiele der Seele. Traum, Imagination und künstlerisches Tun, by Hans-Helmut Decker-Voigt, 1992; paperback; entire volume in German except for Moore's piece (Box 11)
    - "A world of mentors" in If I were your daddy, this is what you'd learn, edited by Julia Espey, 2010; includes letter of appreciation from author (Box 11)
    - "The soul makes us human" in Invitations to dialog: The legacy of Sideny M. Jourard, edited by Anne Richards and Tiparat Schumrun, 1999; paperback (Box 11)
    - "Marsilio Ficino: Magus and cultural visionary" in Friend to mankind: Marsilio Ficino 1433-1499 edited by Michael Shepherd, 1999; paperback; 2 copies (Box 11)
    - "Jesus Hermes and shifting worlds: Metanoia as therapy" in Disturbances in the field, edited by Christine Downing, 2006; paperback (Box 11)
    - "Thomas Moore" in 100 words, 200 visionaries, edited by William Murtha, 2010; paperback; not really a chapter, just 2 pages from each contributor (Box 11)
    - "The Sacred arts of life" in Spirit of simplicity, 1996?; paperback; excerpt from Care of the Soul (Box 11)
  - Forewords, prefaces, introductions
    - Best spiritual writing 2000, edited by Philip Zaleski (Box 11)
    - The Buddha and the terrorist, by Satish Kumar, 2006 (Box 11)
    - Four faces, by Mark Tully, 1997 (Box 11)
    - God's breath: Sacred scriptures of the world, edited by John Miller and Aaron Kenedi, 2000 (Box 11)
    - Gregorian chant: Songs of the spirit, edited by Huston Smith, 1996; includes music CD in pocket inside back cover (Box 11)
    - Intimate kisses: The poetry of sexual pleasure, edited by Wendy Maltz, 2001 (Box 11)
    - Jamila, by Chingiz Aitmatov, 1999 (Box 11)
    - The Shadow in America: Reclaiming the soul of a nation, edited by Jeremiah Abrams, 1994 (Box 11)
    - Shelter fo the spirit, by Victoria Moran, 1997 (Box 11)
    - The Soul in grief, by Robert Romanyshyn, 1999; signed and inscribed to Moore (Box 11)
    - Storytelling with children, by Nancy Mellon, 2000 (Box 11)
    - Time shifting, by Stephan Rechtschaffen, 1996; signed and inscribed to Moore (Box 11)
    - The War on pain, by Scott Fishman, 2000 (Box 11)
    - Work and the life of the spirit, edited by Douglas Thorpe, 1998 (Box 11)
  - Interviews with
    - America West, 1993 (Box 8)
    - American Way, 1994 (Box 8)
    - Bottom Line, 1993 (Box 8)
    - Common Boundary, 1992 (Box 8)
    - Journal of Family Life, 1995; 2000 (Box 8)
    - Journeymen, 1993 (Box 8)
    - Lotus, 1996 (Box 8)
    - N-O, 1992-1993; 1999; New Dimensions, Orbit, Quaker Life (Box 8)
    - Science of Mind, 1995 (Box 8)
    - Troubadour, 1994; in German (Box 8)
    - U, 1993; 2009; Unified Health; Uptown Express (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous newspapers (Box 8)
  - Journal articles
    - "L'Art de contempler," Initiations, numero 13, 1996; in French (Box 11)
    - "Beauty and the reanimation of things," Pilgrimage, vol. 18 no. 3, 1992 (Box 11)
    - "Body and soul," Topics in geriatric rehabilitation, vol. 19 no. 4, 2003 (Box 11)
    - "Commentary: The sacred art of psychotherapy," Journal of integrative and eclectic psychotherapy, vol. 6 no. 3, 1987 (Box 11)
    - "Friendship and platonic love," Monet Senario, vol. 3 no. 9, 1999; entire volume is in Italian except for Moore's piece (Box 11)
    - "Re-morse: An initiatory disturbance of the soul," The Psychotherapy Patient vol. 5 no. 1/2, 1988 (Box 11)
  - Magazine articles
    - B, 1993; 1999; Body and Soul; Business Ethics (Box 12)
    - Complete Woman, 1996 (Box 12)
    - Daily Word, 1998 (Box 12)
    - Forbes, 1996 (Box 12)
    - i to i [Eye to Eye], 1994 (Box 12)
    - Inward Springs, 1998 (Box 12)
    - Lapis no. 7 (Box 12)
    - Liguorian, 1995-1996; 2000,; 2002 (Box 12)
    - New Age, 1995 (Box 12)
    - P, 1993-1996; Parabola; Praying; Psychology Today; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Reform, 2010 (Box 12)
    - Resurgence, 1996; 1998,; 2000,; 2002-2003,; 2006-2007,; 2010; 6 folders (Box 13)
    - Salt Journal, 1997 (Box 13)
    - Spirituality & Health, 1996-2000; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Spirituality & Health, 2001-2003; 2007-2010; 8 folders (Box 14)
    - The Sun, 1998; 2001 (Box 15)
    - This Old House, 2001 (Box 15)
    - Tikkun, 1998; 2000,; 2003-2004; 2 folders (Box 15)
    - Trinity News, 1995 (Box 15)
    - T misc, 1997; 2003; Transition; TV Guide (Box 15)
    - The World and I, 1992 (Box 15)
    - Yoga Journal, 1994 (Box 15)
  - Newspaper articles
    - Miscellaneous newspapers, 2010 (Box 15)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Calendar (Box 11)
    - Magazines, no clear connection, 2 folders (Box 15)